Chapter 127. The deck.
The coffin laid upon two line tubs between the vice bench and the open
hatchway. the carpenter cocking its seams, the string of twisted oakum
slowly unwinding from a large roll of it placed in the bosom of his frock. Ahab
comes slowly from the cabin gang way and here's Pip following him.
Back, lad. I will be with you again presently.
He goes, "Not this hand complies with my humor more genially than that boy.
Middle aisle of a church. What's here? A life boy, sir. Mr. Starbucks orders. Oh,
look, sir. Beware the hatchway. Thank you, ma'am. Thy coffin lies handy to the
vault, sir. The hatchway. Oh. Uh, so it does, sir. Uh, so it does. Art thou not
the leg maker? Look, did not this stump come from thy shop? I believe it did,
sir. Does the feral stand, sir?
Well enough. But art thou not also the undertaker?
I sir, I patched up this thing here as a coffin for Quiqu, but they've set me now
to turning it into something else.
Then tell me, art thou not an errant, all grasping, intermeding, monopolizing,
heathenish old scamp, to be one day making legs, and the next day coffins to
clap them in, and yet again life boys out of those same coffins. Thou art as
unprincipled as the gods, and as much of a jack of all trades.
But I do not mean anything, sir. I do as I do.
The gods again. Hark ye. Dust thou not ever sing about a coffin? The titans,
they say, hum snatches when chipping out the craters for volcanoes, and the
gravedigger in the play sings spade in hand. Dust thou never sing, sir? Do I sing? Oh, I'm
indifferent enough, sir, for that. But the reason why the gravedigger made
music must have been because there was none in his spade, sir. But the cocking
mallet is full of it. Hark to it. I And that's because the lid there's a
sounding board. And what in all things makes the sounding board is this?
There's not beneath. And yet a coffin with a body in it rings pretty much the
same. Carpenter, hast thou ever helped carry a beer and heard the coffin knock
against the churchyard gate going in?
Faith, sir, I faith. What's that?
Why faith, sir? It's only a sort of exclamation like that's all, sir.
Go on. I was about to say, sir, that art thou a silkworm? Dust thou spin thy own
shroud out of thyself?
Look at thy bosom. Dispatch, and get these traps out of sight,
he goes after. That was sudden now, but squalls come sudden in hot latitudes.
I've heard that the aisle of Albamarl, one of the Galapagos, is cut by the
equator right in the middle. Seems to me some sort of equator cuts yan old man,
too, right in his middle. He's always under the line. Fiery hot, I tell you.
He's looking this way. Come, Oak, quick.
Here we go again. This wooden mallet is the cork, and I'm the professor of
musical glasses. Tap tap.
Ahab to himself.
There's a sight. There's a sound. The gay-headed woodpecker tapping the hollow
tree. Blind and dumb might well be envied now. See, that thing rests on two
line tubs full of tow lines. A most malicious wag that fellow. Rat tat. So
man's seconds tick. Oh, how immaterial are all materials. What things real are
there but imponderable thoughts? Here now is the very dreaded symbol of grim
death by a mere hap made the expressive sign of the help and hope of most
endangered life. A life boy of a coffin.
Does it go further? Can it be that in some spiritual sense the coffin is after
all but an immortality preserver?
I'll think of that. But no. So far gone,
am I in the dark side of Earth, that its other side, the theoretic bright one,
seems but uncertain twilight to me.
Will you never have done, Carpenter, with that oursided sound?
I go below. Let me not see that thing here when I return again.
Now then, Pip, we'll talk this over. I do suck most wondrous philosophies from
thee. Some unknown conduits from the unknown worlds must empty into thee.